<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.ayuislands.theme</id>
    <name>Ayu Islands</name>
    <!-- version patched by Gradle from gradle.properties -->
    <vendor email="roman.borodavkin@gmail.com"
            url="https://github.com/barad1tos/ayu-jetbrains">ayu-islands
    </vendor>
    <resource-bundle>messages.AyuIslandsBundle</resource-bundle>

    <description><![CDATA[
    <p><i>Not another color swap — a unified aesthetic engine for every JetBrains IDE.</i></p>

    <p>Ayu Islands goes beyond color porting. It synchronizes palette, font, glow,
    and accent into a cohesive look — one click, the entire mood shift.
    Built on <a href="https://github.com/ayu-theme/ayu-colors">ayu-colors</a> (MIT)
    and <b>endorsed by the original Ayu creator</b>.
    Free to install — all premium features unlocked for 30 days.</p>

    <h3>What sets it apart</h3>
    <ul>
      <li><b>Aesthetic engine, not a skin</b> — 500+ hand-tuned UI properties,
          expanded semantic highlighting, and dedicated settings panels to shape
          how the IDE looks and feels</li>
      <li><b>4 curated presets</b> — Whisper, Ambient, Neon, Cyberpunk. Each
          synchronizes font, glow intensity, and indent colors into one
          cohesive mood</li>
      <li><b>Syntax control surface</b> — language-aware syntax presets for
          everyone, plus Pro-level Custom tuning and readability controls when
          you want comments, docs, and operators to recede.</li>
      <li><b>Plugin ecosystem</b> — accent color propagates into CodeGlance Pro
          and Indent Rainbow. One palette, everywhere — no other theme does this</li>
      <li><b>Creator-endorsed</b> — Ike Ku (<a href="https://github.com/dempfi">@dempfi</a>),
          the author of the original Ayu theme, called this project
          <i>"brilliant"</i> and invited it to
          <a href="https://ayutheme.com">ayutheme.com</a></li>
    </ul>

    <h3>Premium — make the IDE feel yours</h3>
    <ul>
      <li><b>Glow</b> — a soft light beneath tabs and panels: Soft, Sharp Neon,
          or Gradient. Add Pulse, Breathe, or Reactive animation. Control
          intensity, width, and which of the 7 panels glow.</li>
      <li><b>Accent control</b> — decide exactly where your accent color
          appears: scrollbars, links, caret line, search highlights, progress
          bars, bracket matches, inlay hints, tag matches. Eight independent
          switches.</li>
      <li><b>Accent rotation</b> — automatic preset cycling or contrast-aware
          random. Your IDE palette evolves on its own.</li>
      <li><b>Per-project accent pins</b> — bind a color to a specific project;
          it applies whenever you focus that window, no keyboard shortcut
          needed.</li>
      <li><b>Per-language accent pins</b> — bind a color to a language
          (Kotlin → cyan, Python → gold); applies when the project's dominant
          language matches and no project override exists. Settings shows a
          live <b>language-proportions</b> breakdown for the current project
          so you can see which pin takes effect. <b>Language override diagnostics</b>
          explain detected, polyglot, forced-language, and project-fallback
          decisions without changing the default dominance logic.
          <b>Rescan Project Language</b> on demand from the proportions row
          or the Tools menu.</li>
      <li><b>Peacock-parity chrome tinting</b> — when a project / language
          accent fires, every chrome surface (status bar, nav bar, tool
          stripes, panel borders) tints automatically. Intensity slider in
          Settings → Theme Synchronization. WCAG-aware foreground keeps
          text readable at any saturation. Inspired by Peacock for VS Code
          (johnpapa.net), built on JetBrains primitives — not ported.</li>
      <li><b>Accent from project icon</b> — when enabled, projects without a
          pin take their accent from the project icon (.idea/icon.png)
          automatically on open; the Add Override dialog offers the icon's dominant color
          as a one-click pick.</li>
      <li><b>VCS color customization</b> — Settings → Ayu Islands → VCS
          tunes intensity across five surfaces (diff viewer, Project View
          file status, editor gutter, conflict markers, Git blame
          annotations). Per-section profiles: Whisper, Ambient, Neon,
          Cyberpunk, or Custom with per-surface sliders. Master toggle
          stays off by default so 2.6.2 colors are byte-identical until
          users opt in.</li>
      <li><b>Syntax tuning</b> — Settings → Ayu Islands → Syntax adds a Custom
          mode with per-language sliders for declarations, identifiers,
          keywords, docs, literals, and operators, plus global readability
          switches for dimming comments, softening docs, quieting operators,
          and emphasizing declarations.</li>
      <li><b>Workspace</b> — auto-fit or fixed width for Project View, Commit,
          and Git panels with min/max bounds. Git panel splitter control for
          branches and file changes trees. Hide the filesystem path and
          scrollbar from the Project View. Commit Panel path display can move
          full paths to tooltips or shorten leading directories inline.</li>
      <li><b>Tab styling</b> — Islands UI: underline, full accent bar, or none.
          Classic UI: underline thickness from hairline to bold.</li>
      <li><b>Plugin sync</b> — accent into CodeGlance Pro minimap and Indent
          Rainbow guides (3 Ayu presets). More integrations in development.</li>
      <li><b>Bracket scope</b> — a colored gutter stripe showing the full
          scope when your cursor lands on a bracket.</li>
      <li><b>Onboarding wizard</b> — a full-tab welcome on first install with
          preset cards, theme variant picker, and accent swatches. After
          upgrades, a <b>release showcase</b> tab opens automatically with
          captioned screenshots of the marquee features; reopen anytime from
          Tools → Ayu Islands.</li>
      <li><b>Font presets</b> — 4 curated Nerd Fonts with one-click apply.
          <b>Install, delete, or reinstall fonts</b> directly from Settings —
          every filesystem change gets a consent dialog showing the exact
          folder path.</li>
      <li><b>Quick-Switcher Widget</b> — a chip in the main toolbar reflects
          your current accent. Left-click for variant, accent, related toggles,
          and quick actions; right-click for the same actions in a keyboard-
          friendly context menu.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><b>Try everything free for 30 days.</b> No credit card.
    Install, explore, decide later.</p>

    <h3>Free — a complete theme, not a teaser</h3>

    <p>6 theme variants (Mirage, Dark, Light — Classic &amp; Islands UI).
    40+ individually crafted language syntaxes, expanded semantic highlighting,
    and four one-click syntax presets.
    12 accent presets + custom picker + macOS system sync.
    4 font presets with one-click apply and live preview.
    Full VCS/diff colors and a 16-color terminal scheme.
    All free. No time limit. No feature degradation.</p>
  ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
    <h3>2.8.0</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Chrome tint on external themes</b> — selected chrome surfaces and the active tab underline can now follow the Ayu accent on non-Ayu themes when explicitly enabled; external chrome tint stays off by default.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Glow placement</b> — choose where glow renders: the full island frame or its side edges only, per surface (editor and tool windows); clicks preview on the live window instantly, Apply keeps them.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>ECG waveform glow</b> — trace the focused island with a continuous phosphor-comet perimeter loop whose pace responds to typing; configure its direction, loop duration, trace length, spike density, border position, amplitude, and intensity without changing saved solid-glow preferences.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Accent from project icon</b> — when enabled, projects without an override take their accent from .idea/icon.png automatically when they open; the Add Override dialog offers the icon's dominant color as a one-click pick.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Commit panel accessibility crash</b> — screen-reader and macOS accessibility walks over the commit changes tree no longer flood idea.log with "Attempt to take read lock was prevented" errors; the path renderer serves plain text when the platform forbids model access mid-walk.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Find what's new faster</b> — the settings page now points at newly added controls: a "New in this release" index with a Review jump link, an accent dot on tabs that contain new settings, and small "New" marks on the rows themselves; everything clears as you visit and never outlives 45 days.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.8</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Fix] <b>What's New and onboarding tabs</b> — a failed tab open no longer blocks the What's New tab or the license wizard for the rest of the IDE session; the next trigger simply retries.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Accent apply recovery</b> — when applying an accent fails midway, the color now recovers on the next window focus instead of freezing until restart, and startup only trusts cached accents from a cleanly finished apply.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Accent rotation reliability</b> — rotation now counts failed applies and stops with the "accent rotation stopped" notification instead of silently ticking forever against a broken apply.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>License downgrade revert</b> — the "restart to complete the reset" notice now appears when the free-tier revert could not finish cleanly.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Settings overrides preview</b> — opening the Accent → Overrides resolution preview is now strictly read-only and never schedules background language scans.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Resolution diagnostics consistency</b> — the "Currently active" label, the diagnostics row, and the accent actually applied now always name the same resolution source.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Project-language accent scans</b> — background detection now cancels when a project closes, checks cancellation during large repository scans, and drops late cache or publish results so reopened projects do not inherit stale language accents.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Large project language accents</b> — language detection now keeps exact scans for projects under the file cap and uses bounded sampling for larger repositories, so accents resolve consistently without walking every file in a monorepo.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Font installer fallbacks</b> — fallback font download URLs are now smoke-checked in CI before release, catching broken upstream links before a bundled font install reaches users.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.7</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Language override diagnostics</b> — Settings and Quick-Switcher now show the detected project-language breakdown, manual forced-language state, polyglot fallback detail, and the language that actually won accent resolution.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Mapped accents in mixed-language projects</b> — polyglot scans can now choose the highest-weight detected language that has a user accent mapping, so balanced projects can still use a configured language color instead of falling back to the global accent.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Swift and Noctule Swift highlighting</b> — Swift declaration and reference aliases, predefined symbols, and <code>nil</code> fallback now use Ayu-native semantic colors across Dark, Mirage, and Light.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Project fallback accents</b> — project fallback resolution now warms and reuses the detector verdict consistently, keeping diagnostics aligned with the accent that gets applied.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Font install consent</b> — Settings and onboarding font installs now require the exact catalog entry that the user approved before any font files are queued for installation.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.6</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Language override diagnostics</b> — Quick-Switcher now keeps dominant-language proportions and fallback detail in the expanded resolution chain instead of crowding or overlapping the collapsed widget.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Groovy and Jenkinsfile semantic highlighting</b> — Jenkinsfile pipeline calls, named arguments, dynamic Jenkins bindings, and unresolved chained calls now resolve to Ayu-native Groovy semantic colors across Dark, Mirage, and Light.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Jenkinsfile unresolved references</b> — pipeline DSL symbols such as <code>properties</code>, <code>parameters</code>, <code>podTemplate</code>, and <code>containerTemplate</code> no longer render as near-background text or carry noisy dotted underlines.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Focus-based accent refresh</b> — switching project windows now reapplies project and language accents through IntelliJ's write-safe dispatch path instead of a raw Swing callback.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Chrome tinting dividers</b> — shared IntelliJ divider peers no longer pick up project accent tint and draw a colored editor frame outside the intended accent surfaces.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.5</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Accent Source status-bar widget</b> — Pro users can add a status-bar widget that shows which accent source won for the current project and opens the full resolution chain.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Language override controls</b> — language accent detection now shows dominance and fallback details in Settings, and forced language or fallback choices take precedence over the global accent.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Quick-Switcher accent diagnostics</b> — the toolbar widget now shows the resolved accent source inline, with an expandable chain for project pins, language overrides, fallbacks, external themes, and global accents.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Groovy and Jenkinsfile syntax colors</b> — Groovy and Jenkinsfile roles now have explicit Ayu colors across Dark, Mirage, and Light, including methods, fields, map keys, strings, GStrings, keywords, documentation, and inlay type hints.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Quick-Switcher widget buttons</b> — related toggle buttons now apply Chrome tinting, Glow, Accent rotation, and Follow system accent changes reliably from the widget.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Chrome tinting target preservation</b> — widget toggles and Settings Apply now preserve the exact chrome tint targets you selected instead of turning every tint surface on or off together.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Language override precedence</b> — forced-language and fallback choices now take precedence over project/global fallback when resolving the active accent.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Accent diagnostics accuracy</b> — Quick-Switcher and status-bar diagnostics now match the actual resolver for language fallback, project fallback, and external automatic accents.</li>
      <li>[Fix] <b>Editor Glow with pinned tabs</b> — Glow overlays now align with editor content when only pinned tabs remain, instead of using a fixed tab-strip fallback.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.4</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Language override diagnostics</b> — Settings now explains whether a project's language accent is detected, polyglot, forced to a specific language, or using a project fallback.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Swift semantic highlighting</b> — Noctule Swift files now render parameters, labels, properties, functions, and types with distinct Ayu colors across 109 semantic tokens.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Swift syntax colors</b> — Swift keywords, strings, numbers, and comments use Ayu palette colors in base themes.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.3</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Commit Panel path display</b> — Pro users can move full Commit Panel paths to tooltips or shorten leading directories inline.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Syntax preview</b> — native highlighting now updates reliably when switching syntax presets and readability options.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.2</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] <b>External theme accent inheritance</b> — Pro project and language accent pins can now drive selected Ayu integrations while another IDE theme is active.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Glow on external themes</b> — Glow can follow Ayu accents on non-Ayu themes when explicitly enabled; external Glow stays off by default.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Plugin sync on external themes</b> — CodeGlance Pro and Indent Rainbow can now sync to Ayu's external accent context on non-Ayu themes.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>External Quick-Switcher actions</b> — premium actions like Random, Lighter, and Darker now persist the chosen external accent on non-Ayu themes.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>External theme support</b> — use selected Ayu accent enhancements on non-Ayu JetBrains themes without switching the active IDE theme to Ayu.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Quick-Switcher on external themes</b> — Quick-Switcher now supports external themes, including accent preset apply and copy flows when external theme support is enabled.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Automatic external accent sources</b> — external accents can resolve from Material Theme, IDE accent colors, or a manual fallback.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.1</h3>
    <ul>
      <li><b>Added:</b> when the optional <code>.ignore</code> plugin is installed, its files use dedicated Ayu colors across Dark, Mirage, and Light editor schemes, including Syntax preset transformations and a Plugins-tab opt-out.</li>
      <li><b>Changed:</b> free users can inspect premium Settings controls in their real layout, with controls greyed out until a license or trial unlocks them.</li>
      <li><b>Changed:</b> the VCS tab now shows one compact code-style preview that reflects diff, merge/conflict, blame, and file-status presets together.</li>
      <li><b>Changed:</b> the Font tab now uses the same editor-style preview treatment as VCS, with clearer depth and file context.</li>
      <li><b>Fixed:</b> premium Settings controls stay visible-but-locked across VCS, Glow, Workspace, Chrome tinting, Accent Elements, plugin integrations, and accent overrides instead of disappearing behind a Pro notice.</li>
      <li><b>Fixed:</b> locked premium controls no longer mark Settings as modified when clicked by unlicensed users, and Reset/Revert restores nested plugin-integration rows correctly.</li>
      <li><b>Fixed:</b> Settings tabs and preview panels shrink more consistently in narrow Settings windows.</li>
      <li><b>Fixed:</b> Accent Settings preview stays synchronized with the selected color instead of restoring stale shuffle state.</li>
      <li><b>Fixed:</b> visible managed tool windows re-measure after layout and theme refreshes, so auto-fit sizing stays consistent.</li>
      <li><b>Compatibility:</b> release builds now block IntelliJ Plugin Verifier internal API findings before Marketplace upload.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.7.0</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Free] <b>Expanded semantic highlighting</b> — Ayu Islands now covers hundreds more editor keys across 26+ language families, with focused passes for YAML/HCL, Scala docs, Kotlin gaps, Dart accessors, Groovy, and Go exported identifiers.</li>
      <li>[Free] <b>Syntax presets</b> — the new Settings → Ayu Islands → Syntax tab gives everyone four one-click syntax moods: <b>Whisper</b>, <b>Ambient</b>, <b>Neon</b>, and <b>Cyberpunk</b>.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Custom syntax tuning</b> — Pro users can tune each language separately with sliders for declarations, identifiers, keywords/docs, literals, and operators while untouched cells inherit the selected base preset.</li>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Readability controls</b> — Dim comments, Soften documentation, Quiet operators, and Emphasize declarations layer on top of the active preset so dense code gets quieter without manual per-key Color Scheme editing.</li>
      <li><b>Fixed:</b> matching tag highlights are calmer, status bar text stays readable on tinted chrome, and low chrome-tint values stay subtle instead of jumping straight to saturated accent color.</li>
      <li><b>Fixed:</b> YAML/HCL semantic keys, HCL block names, Syntax Custom layout/opening, preset intensity ordering, and custom reapply now behave consistently across newer IDEs and theme changes.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.6.4</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Free] <b>Quick-Switcher Widget</b> — a new chip in the main toolbar reflects the focused project's accent. Left-click opens a popup with the variant and Islands UI toggle, the full accent grid, related toggles (Chrome tinting, Glow, Accent rotation, Follow system), and quick actions (Pin, Random, Lighter, Darker, Copy Hex). Right-click opens the same actions as a context menu for a keyboard-friendly workflow.</li>
      <li>Premium rows (toggles and quick actions) appear when your license is active or in trial; the FREE block (variant and accent grid) is available to everyone.</li>
      <li>Hide the widget anytime from Settings → Ayu Islands → General if you prefer a cleaner toolbar.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.6.3</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] <b>A new VCS tab</b> — tune VCS color intensity across five surfaces (diff viewer, Project View file status, editor gutter, conflict markers, Git blame annotations). Pick a named profile — <b>Whisper</b> (calmer), <b>Ambient</b> (2.6.2 defaults), <b>Neon</b> (brighter, pre-2.6.2 punch), or <b>Cyberpunk</b> (peak) — or dial each surface independently in Custom mode. The master toggle stays off by default, so colors are byte-identical to 2.6.2 until you opt in.</li>
      <li>Settings → Ayu Islands → <b>VCS</b> tab now lives between Glow and Workspace.</li>
      <li>Project tool window no longer changes width when toggled on/off in Mirage Islands UI under auto-fit mode (issue #169).</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.6.2</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>VCS modified-line color is now distinct from added — modified shifts to a saturated blue (Dark <code>#73B8FF</code>, Mirage <code>#80BFFF</code>) so it stops blending into the green added band on dense diffs. Bluer file-status colors in Project View and tabs as well.</li>
      <li>Editor selection background returns to translucent (alpha 25%) on Dark and Mirage, so highlighted text doesn't read as a solid blue block.</li>
      <li>The Settings page no longer freezes on "Loading…" forever when a Custom font preset is active (issue #164) — non-curated presets now skip the font installation pipeline cleanly instead of crashing the panel build.</li>
      <li>The font preview pane now renders the user's chosen Custom font family when Settings opens instead of falling back to "Install JetBrains Mono to preview" — a UX bug previously masked by the panel-build freeze.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.6.1</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Calmed diff backgrounds across Dark, Light, and Mirage variants — modified diff no longer blends with text selection</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.6.0</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] <b>Peacock parity for JetBrains</b> — pin an accent to a project window or to a programming language and every chrome surface (status bar, nav bar, tool stripes, panel borders) tints with that accent automatically. WCAG-aware foreground keeps text readable at any saturation. Inspired by Peacock for VS Code (johnpapa.net) — built on JetBrains primitives, not ported.</li>
      <li>Auto-bind the matching editor color scheme on theme change — switch Ayu Mirage / Dark / Light variants and the editor scheme follows. Default ON; opt-out toggle in Settings → Theme Synchronization preserves your custom scheme (Solarized, Material, etc.) untouched.</li>
      <li>Fix glow lingering after switching to a non-Ayu theme — overlays now dispose cleanly when the active theme leaves the Ayu family</li>
      <li>Fix sticky-line panel transparency in the editor — code under the scope-header line no longer bleeds through</li>
      <li>Fix Indent Rainbow and CodeGlance Pro integrations not reverting cleanly when their sync toggles are turned off</li>
      <li>Fix path widget breadcrumb on IntelliJ 2026.1 New UI Compact Navigation — chrome tinting reads with stable contrast at every intensity, slider visibly tints in a single Apply click</li>
      <li><b>Coming next:</b> commit your accent into <code>.idea/</code> so a whole team sees one color · distinguish Remote / WSL / DevContainer / Code With Me windows at a glance · one-keystroke darken/lighten on the active accent · named favorite colors · every Peacock command available through Find Action</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.5.3</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] Rescan project language on demand — new "Rescan" link in the Overrides proportions row and "Tools → Ayu Islands → Rescan Project Language" menu action, for when you want the detected breakdown to refresh without waiting for the next Gradle sync</li>
      <li>Bug fixes</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.5.2</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] Per-Language Accent Pins now show a live breakdown of the detected languages in your project (e.g. "Detected: Kotlin 78% • Java 15% • other 7%") or a clear "polyglot" notice when no single language dominates</li>
      <li>Fix accent rotation overriding pinned project colors — tabs and glow now stay on your pinned accent across rotation ticks</li>
      <li>Fix the Settings panel readouts for currently active and detected projects binding to the wrong project when two or more windows are open.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.5.1</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Updated Marketplace "About" description to cover all v2.5.0 features — per-project and per-language accent pins, onboarding wizard, and the first-launch release showcase tab — that hadn't made it onto the listing page</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.5.0</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] Pin an accent color to a specific project — set it once from Settings, and every time you switch to that window, your accent is there.</li>
      <li>[Paid] Pin an accent color to a programming language — e.g., Kotlin → lime, Python → sky. It applies when a project's dominant language matches and no project override exists.</li>
      <li>Recent projects populate the add-project dialog so you can configure overrides without opening the project first</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.4.2</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] Install, delete, or reinstall curated fonts directly from Settings without opening the wizard</li>
      <li>Every font installation and deletion now shows a consent dialog with the exact font folder path — no silent filesystem changes.</li>
      <li>When you delete a font, the editor reverts to JetBrains Mono and warns that complete removal takes effect after an IDE restart.</li>
      <li>The Settings page now shows "Installed ✓", "file missing — Reinstall", or "Install automatically" based on the actual disk state.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.4.1</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Fix the font installation retry getting stuck on a corrupted download cache</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.4.0</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Onboarding wizard — full-tab welcome experience with preset cards, theme variant picker, and accent swatches</li>
      <li>[Paid] Font installation — download and apply curated coding fonts directly from the wizard</li>
      <li>Responsive scaling — wizard adapts to split editors and small windows</li>
      <li>Fix trial day calculation timezone drift (UTC instead of system default)</li>
      <li>Renewing a license preserves your existing settings</li>
      <li>Mid-session license changes apply immediately</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.3.7</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Free] Fix tool window width jumping when switching between panels</li>
      <li>[Paid] Hide editor scrollbars while preserving scroll functionality</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.3.6</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Bug fixes</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.3.5</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Fix selection overlap bands when accent color is active on multi-row selections</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.3.4</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Fix glow color desyncing from accent after rotation</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.3.3</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Fix "Write-unsafe context" crash during accent rotation with Indent Rainbow</li>
      <li>Rewrite Marketplace description</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.3.2</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] Accent rotation — automatic preset cycling or contrast-aware random</li>
      <li>[Free] Shuffle UI redesign with heroic accent indicator</li>
      <li>Fix trial</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.3.1</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Bug fixes</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>2.3.0</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>[Paid] Auto-fit with configurable min/max width for Project View, Commit, and Git panels</li>
      <li>[Paid] Git panel internal splitter control — auto-resize branches tree and file changes tree</li>
      <li>[Paid] Project View cleanup — hide the filesystem path and horizontal scrollbar</li>
      <li>[Free] 30-day premium trial — every premium feature unlocked on the first install, no credit card</li>
      <li>[Free] Returning users get a fresh trial with premium defaults re-applied</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Full changelog: <a href="https://github.com/barad1tos/ayu-jetbrains/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md">GitHub</a></p>
  ]]></change-notes>

    <!-- idea-version patched by Gradle from gradle.properties -->
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends optional="true" config-file="groovy.xml">org.intellij.groovy</depends>
    <!-- Noctule Swift plugin id verified from its installed plugin.xml on 2026-06-30. -->
    <depends optional="true" config-file="noctule-swift.xml">dev.j-a.swift</depends>
    <depends optional="true" config-file="codeglance-pro.xml">com.nasller.CodeGlancePro</depends>
    <depends optional="true" config-file="indent-rainbow.xml">indent-rainbow.indent-rainbow</depends>

    <!-- JetBrains ties release-date to the paid product release-version. Keep
         this date aligned with the existing Marketplace entry for the same
         release-version; changing it without bumping release-version makes
         Marketplace reject the upload. -->
    <product-descriptor
            code="PAYUISLANDS"
            release-date="20260529"
            release-version="27"
            optional="true"/>

    <extensionPoints>
        <extensionPoint
                name="accentElement"
                interface="dev.ayuislands.accent.AccentElement"
                dynamic="true"/>
    </extensionPoints>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.ayuislands.theme">
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.InlayHintsElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.CaretRowElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.ProgressBarElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.ScrollbarElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.LinksElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.BracketMatchElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.SearchResultsElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.MatchingTagElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.StatusBarElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.MainToolbarElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.ToolWindowStripeElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.NavBarElement"/>
        <accentElement implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.elements.PanelBorderElement"/>
    </extensions>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <!-- Settings panel under Appearance > Ayu Islands -->
        <applicationConfigurable
                parentId="appearance"
                instance="dev.ayuislands.settings.AyuIslandsConfigurable"
                id="dev.ayuislands.settings.AyuIslandsConfigurable"
                bundle="messages.AyuIslandsBundle"
                key="configurable.display.name"/>

        <!-- Persistent accent color state -->
        <applicationService
                serviceImplementation="dev.ayuislands.settings.AyuIslandsSettings"/>

        <!-- Per-project and per-language accent overrides -->
        <applicationService
                serviceImplementation="dev.ayuislands.settings.mappings.AccentMappingsSettings"/>

        <!-- Syntax intensity persistent state -->
        <applicationService
                serviceImplementation="dev.ayuislands.syntax.SyntaxIntensityState"/>

        <!-- Plugin lifecycle -->
        <postStartupActivity
                implementation="dev.ayuislands.AyuIslandsStartupActivity"/>

        <!-- Trial expiry notifications -->
        <notificationGroup id="Ayu Islands"
                           key="notification.group.ayu-islands"
                           displayType="BALLOON"/>

        <!-- Onboarding wizard editor tab -->
        <fileEditorProvider
                implementation="dev.ayuislands.onboarding.OnboardingEditorProvider"/>

        <!-- Free onboarding wizard editor tab -->
        <fileEditorProvider
                implementation="dev.ayuislands.onboarding.FreeOnboardingEditorProvider"/>

        <!-- What's New release showcase editor tab -->
        <fileEditorProvider
                implementation="dev.ayuislands.whatsnew.WhatsNewEditorProvider"/>

        <!-- Mirage variants -->
        <themeProvider id="com.ayuislands.theme.mirage"
                       path="/themes/ayu-islands-mirage.theme.json"/>
        <themeProvider id="com.ayuislands.theme.mirage.islands"
                       path="/themes/ayu-islands-mirage-islands.theme.json"/>
        <!-- Dark variants -->
        <themeProvider id="com.ayuislands.theme.dark"
                       path="/themes/ayu-islands-dark.theme.json"/>
        <themeProvider id="com.ayuislands.theme.dark.islands"
                       path="/themes/ayu-islands-dark-islands.theme.json"/>
        <!-- Light variants -->
        <themeProvider id="com.ayuislands.theme.light"
                       path="/themes/ayu-islands-light.theme.json"/>
        <themeProvider id="com.ayuislands.theme.light.islands"
                       path="/themes/ayu-islands-light-islands.theme.json"/>

        <!-- Accent source status bar widget (premium) -->
        <statusBarWidgetFactory
                id="AyuIslands.AccentStatusBar"
                implementation="dev.ayuislands.accent.statusbar.AccentStatusBarWidgetFactory"/>
    </extensions>

    <applicationListeners>
        <listener
                class="dev.ayuislands.AyuIslandsAppListener"
                topic="com.intellij.ide.AppLifecycleListener"/>
        <listener
                class="dev.ayuislands.AyuIslandsLafListener"
                topic="com.intellij.ide.ui.LafManagerListener"/>
        <listener
                class="dev.ayuislands.AppearanceSyncListener"
                topic="com.intellij.openapi.application.ApplicationActivationListener"/>
        <listener
                class="dev.ayuislands.licensing.LicenseTransitionListener"
                topic="com.intellij.ui.LicensingFacade$LicenseStateListener"/>
        <!-- Drop the language-detector cache on project close so canonical-path-keyed
             entries don't leak when a project is renamed / reopened at the same path -->
        <listener
                class="dev.ayuislands.accent.ProjectLanguageCacheInvalidator"
                topic="com.intellij.openapi.project.ProjectManagerListener"/>
    </applicationListeners>

    <actions>
        <action id="AyuIslands.ShowWhatsNew"
                class="dev.ayuislands.whatsnew.ShowWhatsNewAction">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>

        <group id="AyuIslands.ToolsGroup"
               popup="true">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <action id="AyuIslands.RescanLanguage"
                    class="dev.ayuislands.actions.RescanLanguageAction"/>
        </group>

        <action id="AyuIslands.QuickSwitcher"
                class="dev.ayuislands.accent.toolbar.QuickSwitcherWidgetAction">
            <add-to-group group-id="MainToolbarRight" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
